Guide to the Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers AIS.2011.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Women at Pitt Research File, 1895-1986; VI.
  - School of Business Administration and Economics, 1910-1926 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - School of Dentistry, 1908-1926 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - School of Education, 1919-1926 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - School of Engineering, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - School of Medicine, 1903-1933 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - School of Nursing, 1939-1953 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - School of Pharmacy, 1903-1908 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Senior Queen Ceremony, 1926-1957 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Sexual Discrimination, 1969-1986 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Smoking, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Stein Sisters: Margaret Lydia and Stella Mathilde, 1895-1939 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Student Organizations, 1911-1936 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Student Organization Handbook, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Student Organizations Tally, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Thrysa Amos, 1919-1941 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Tuition, 1915-1942 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - University of Pittsburgh History, 1895-1987 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Vade Mecum, 1923-1950 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Women's Association, 1977-2003 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Women's Organizations, 1972-1977 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Women's SELF Governance Association, 1916-1986 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Women's Studies Program, 1972-1995 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Women's Work Conference, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Young Women's Christian Association, 1915-1986 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Affirmative Action Addition, 1970-71 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action News and Publication 1 of 2, 1971-72 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Affirmative Action News and Publication 2 of 2, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Proposal for Feminist Studies, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Women's Studies Program Five Year Report, 1972-1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Pittsburgh Radical Women's Union, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Histroy of the National Council of Women's Organisations (ACWO), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - National Organization for Women (Now), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- "The History of Women at Pitt: Reflections on a Changing Society" Exhibit, 1983-1995; VII.
  Series VII contains material related to the 1987 exhibit "The History of Women at Pitt: Reflections on a Changing Society," directed by Carolyn Schumacher, which chronicles the experience of women from 1895-1987 at the University of Pittsburgh. The exhibit was included in the bicentennial celebration of the university. The series includes correspondence, drafts, notes, proposals, publicity, and photographic material related to the project.
  - Administrative Files, 1983-1989; 1986-1988; 1.
    The Administrative Files subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's development, proposal, and execution of the "History of Women at Pitt" Exhibit. The subseries includes correspondence, proposals, grant applications, meeting minutes, newsletters, notes, and publications.
    - Administrative Oversight, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Ann Sutherland Harris: Letter to Chancellor, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Grant from "Friends of Women at Pitt", 1988 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - History Associates, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Institutional Review Board of Psychosocial Research regarding "History of College Education for Women in Pittsburgh", 1988 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Junior League of Pittsburgh: Letter of Intent, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Junior League of Pittsburgh Project and Grant Proposal Guidelines, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Junior League of Pittsburgh Proposal, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Maurice Falk Medical Fund, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Pennsylvania Local History Grant Form, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Project Report to the "Friends of Women at Pitt" and the PACWC, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Proposal for a book on the History of College Women in Pittsburgh, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Proposal for a University Bicentennial Exhibit and Catalog on the History of Women at the University of Pittsburgh, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Prospectus: "Reflections of a Changing Society: The History of Higher Education for Women in Pittsburgh", 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - Provost's Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns: Annual Report, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - Provost's Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns: Meeting Notes, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 117)
    - "Provost's Comments and Charge to First Meeting of Women's Advisory Committee", 1983 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - William Pitt Union Art Gallery Requirements, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - Women's Studies Steering Committee Bicentennial Exhibit, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Exhibit Poster, 1987 (Map-case 32 / 1, Oversize 1)
    - Publications, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Production Files, 1987-1988; 2.
    The Production Files subseries contains materials related to the creation of the physical exhibit of "The History of Women at Pitt." The subseries includes articles, budgets, drafts, outlines, and publicity for the exhibit.
    - Budget, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - Bicentennial Events, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 122)
    - Credits and Contacts, undated (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Exhibit Corrections, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Exhibit Outline, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Illustrations, Graphics, and Photos for Exhibit: Draft Stage, undated (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Invoice for Graphics and Photos, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 127)
    - Notes, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 128)
    - Opening Program for Exhibit, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 129)
    - Panel and Case Organization, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - Publicity, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - University of Pittsburgh Bradford Campus, "The History of Women at Pitt " Article, unfinished, undated (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - "Women at Pitt" from the Pittsburgh Post Gazette, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - History of Women Website, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - History of Women Slides from Website, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - History of Women Text from Site, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - History of Website and Exhibit, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Master Summary of Exhibit, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bicentennial Event Research, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Photo Research, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Panel 1, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Panel 2, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Panel 3, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Panel 4, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Panel 5, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Panel 6 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Panel 7, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Panel 8, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Panel 9, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Panel 10, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Panel 11 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Panel 12, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Panel 13, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Exhibit Programs, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Exhibit Comments/Attendance, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Exhibit Budget,Contract, and Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Pitt Talk Exhibit, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Photographic Material Files, 1987-1988; 3.
    The Photographic Material Files subseries contains photographic materials related to the development of "The History of Women at Pitt: Reflections on a Changing Society" exhibit, including negatives, slides, and printed photographs.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Slides of Exhibit: Production-Final Product, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Exhibit Slides, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Exhibit Negatives, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Exhibit Photos 1 of 3, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Exhibit Photos 2 of 3, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Exhibit Photos 3 of 3, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Women in Higher Education, 1908-1988; VIII.
  Series VII contains materials related to Schumacher's research on women in higher education; while there is some information about women in Pittsburgh, this series focuses on the implications of higher education for women nationwide. The series includes articles and publications, notes, newsletters, and statistical reports.
  - "A Generation of Women: Education in the Lives of Progressive Reformers" by Ellen Condliffe Lagemann, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "A Report and Recommendation by The Carnegie Commisssion on Higher Edcuation", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Mellon, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chatham College, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Co-Education on Two Campuses: Berkeley and Chicago, 1890-1912" by Lynn D. Gordon, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Colby College Exhibit on Coeducation, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Daughters of Main Street: Culture and the Female Community at Grinnell, 1884-1917" by Joan G. Zimmerman, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Duquesne University, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Elizabeth Carroll (Sister), 1987 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Enrollment Nationally, 1979-1984 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Executive Women's Council Directory of Members, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Feminism as Life Process:The Life and Career of Lucy Sprague Mitchell" by Joyce Antler, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Guidelines for Nonsexist Research", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Heritage: Jane Grey Swisshelm" by Donna Murphy Gaither, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Higher Education for Women: From Feminine to Feminist" by Carolyn Schumacher, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Lois Kimball Matthews Rosenberry: A Woman for All Seasons" by Jo Ann Fley, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Oberlin College, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Pearl Buck, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Pennsylvania Federation of Women's Clubs, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Pittsburgh Association for the Advancement of Women Summer Session Courses, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh Educational Institutions, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh Female College, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - The Pittsburgh Record-- Table of Contents, 1926-1936 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Point Park College, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Storer College, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "Teacher Education and Class and Gender Relations: A Critical Analysis of Historical Studies of Teacher Education" by Mark B. Ginsburg, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "The Tender Technicians: The Feminization of Public Librarianship, 1876-1905" by Dee Garrison, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "The Open Gate" by Carolyn Schumacher, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Those Were the Days: Two classes 50 years apart, recall times at UNR" by Scott Trolio, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - West Virginia University, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "The Woman Suffrage Movement: Words and Deeds" Exhibit at Bryn Mawr College, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Women in Academe" by Patricia Albjerg Graham, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Women in Educational Institutions, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Women in Education: Resource Material, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Women of Western Pennsylvania Archives Proposal, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 38)